OK.
OK. So tell me about the bidding,
which is after the tendering, right?
OK.
Right.
So if we fail to find a carrier when
we're tendering,
then we'll do a spot put and that's where
carriers can bid on the freight.
And once a carrier is awarded the freight,
then we tender to them.
So it's it.
You can probably put it as part of 6
tendering and quoting spot quoting.
OK.
So it's like the process of the carrier
saying yes or no, right?
Tendering is yes or no,
and let's just say on average we have 5
OK.
carriers carrier options.
If we can't get any carriers to take the
Right.
freight out of those five,
then we'll send it to a spot put and we
might let 10 carriers bid on the freight
and we'll award one of those carriers.
To move it.
Oh, I see. OK,
so that happens after that then. OK.
Yeah, it it doesn't happen every time,
but it happens after tendering when it
does happen.
But then it loops back to tendering.
So even if we the carrier bids $1000 and
we say we're going to award it to them,
OK.
then we send them a tender with that
$1000 for them to accept.
OK, OK, perfect.
And obviously before that happens,
before that meeting happens,
that is listed as an exception, right?
Or not. OK, so it's stuck. OK,
so bidding is controlled out manually,
Yes.
right?
Well, it can be it can be automated.
So.
And it can be manual.
It depends on the customer.
OK, perfect.
And this is after everything is done
right after the bidding has passed and.
Yeah.
Yep, Yep, here I can show you this.
This visual might help you with that part.
But.
Yeah. You want to share your screen? OK.
Yep. Can you see it?
OK.
So I'm going to focus just on the top
here and the two swim lanes are Odyssey
TMS and customer ERP.
So the customer is going to create an
Mhm.
order and that symbolizes.
One of their customers requesting their
product.
So we create the order and this is an
Odyssey one,
so you can ignore the actual steps,
but we will do the optimization,
create the shipment,
tender the shipment and when when that
shipment is accepted.
Then we send an update to the customer.
Now that's there's no user interface for
that, but that happens.
So the customer now knows who's going to
pick up the freight and when they're
going to pick it up,
and they use that in their system to pick
the freight, pack it,
stage it in their warehouse and load it
onto a truck.
And when they load it onto a truck,
that sends us a message and the whole
purpose of that message is to say we know.
Back here,
what they ordered that could have changed.
And so this message is saying, hey,
we told you we're going to have 5
products and 30,000 lbs.
One of those products got damaged.
So there's only four products and it's 30,
000 lbs.
And then it also tells us like we told
them here that it's going to pick up on
March 23rd and this could say it it
actually picked up on March 24th.
So it's just a few data elements we're
interested in that come in and now we
have to match this file to their shipment.
And that's one of the exceptions is if we
can't find that match.
Now the biggest thing we want to do is we
get information from them that could
change the cost of the shipment.
So we are going to rewrite that shipment
and then we send them a freight accrual
and that goes back up to their system and
this is basically generates accrual so
they know.
What they can expect to be invoiced for
freight that's in transit.
And then the next thing that happens is
uh,
the the invoice comes into the customer.
Does that help at all?
OK.
I think so. The part, the the accrual,
that part was kind of confusing to me
because at that point you already have
your shipment.
The accrual's not for us,
it's for our customer.
OK.
So the customer knows that they have,
let's just say 10 shipments that have
delivered and they might have an invoice
for five of them and they have five more
shipments that are in route.
And so basically they want to know all of
Huh.
the shipments that have been loaded into
a truck that they have not been invoiced
for.
And so this accrual message helps them
with that so that they can know, you know,
it's just for their accounting to say
these orders have all physically left the
building and I can expect an invoice for
them at some point.
I see. OK.
Yeah, again, no user interface for that.
But the whole point of these exceptions
for PGI is so that we can get that
accrual back to them because we need to
be able to successfully re-rate the
shipment and send them the accrual.
Oh, OK.
And and then it does the same thing for
our system.
So we send and if we go back to this swim
lane,
we have our Odyssey billing and payment
which is not in Odyssey one.
So we will send the shipment to Odyssey
one and or to, I'm sorry,
to our financial system and they're gonna
wait.
until they receive an invoice that they
can match that to.
OK, OK, I got you.
Yeah, so um.
I guess this also reflects on the.
Just give me a second.
There is a part in the shipments UI where
it says give me a second.
Uh, cost allocation.
Yeah,
freight cost allocation is the same as
OK.
that accrual.
Or I'm I'm sorry,
sorry we have so many different
Oh, OK, I got you.
terminologies in the UI cost allocation.
This this diagram doesn't really help
with that,
but basically if I have two orders on a
single shipment.
And that shipment cost $1000.
I want to allocate the cost back to each
order and so I can do it by weight.
So if if order one is 60% of the weight,
then it'll represent $600.
00 of the cost and order two would be the
other $400.00 of the cost.
OK,
so you need to split the to split how
much is?
Yeah.
Right.
And it's that's more for that that serves
2 purposes. One is for our customer.
So when we send them the accrued amounts,
they can tie it back to the cost of goods
for that order.
Mhm.
And the the other part is,
so we might have $1000 on the buy side
and that we want to mark up the freight
to charge the customer.
So if we have a 10% mark up,
we're going to charge them 1100.
And if those two orders are for two
different customers,
then we need to know how to charge each
customer for that one buy.
Shipment.
So the first customer,
we might have a 10% markup and the second
Oh, OK.
customer we might have a 20% markup and
we have to mark up the allocated cost so
that it's fairly distributed.
OK. OK. I understand. Now one question,
one other question I have,
it's about APAR cost.
Jenna told me that it would be nice to
Mhm.
have both sitting.
Together so the user can see both prices.
From my understanding APAR, sorry,
Right.
I just sometimes I forget about
everything. APAR costs are about.
Accounts payable and accounts receivable,
right?
Right.
OK,
so both of them have different data sets,
right? Like for example AP costs,
it has a like a detail of everything
that's that's that makes that cost right?
Like for example base rate, fuel,
surcharge, discount.
And up all of that.
And the same goes for AR cost, right?
Right.
Yeah.
That's right. And they they'll,
they'll usually be the same cost types,
Quotes.
right? If there's basin fuel on the AP,
there will be basin fuel in the AR,
but it's not a requirement.
OK, uh,
also another thing I want to know is.
Accounts payable is how much Odyssey is
paying for moving this area and AR cost
Yeah,
that's how much we're gonna pay the
is how much the the client is gonna be
charged, right?
carrier that we tender to.
Correct.
And from there you can have a margin. Oh,
I see.
Yep.
OK.
That that that was important.
Would you like to review it like real
quick? So maybe you have some.
Yeah.
Mm.
Hey.
Checked my calendar and the next meeting
is a town hall so I don't have to be
there.
Oh, OK.
So you can stay with me like for 10 more
Yep, yeah.
minutes.
But I I still need to do the other screen,
the first one that we talk about this
last time,
you know when you selecting the carrier,
sorry, the the client.
And but still I this this is me.
So I I moved the search bar from here to
here because that makes more sense.
We're going to leave that this leave this
one for now.
OK and we're going to use this one.
OK.
So here as I said the other time I just
like search.
Anything,
any shipments and I can say yeah,
this number is.
And let's say by shipment, whatever.
So it it belongs to this and then I
select this and this will show up.
And I know that for example this shipment
has four orders right where I can see
this.
Mhm.
So I can select any of those and this
will show me.
So I think here it's showing me the the
the information about that organ, right?
Yep.
So all of this information is defined in
the orders domain as well,
or there are some stuff here that is
defined elsewhere.
Um.
That should be in the order domain.
I like if you Scroll down I saw Bill's
lighting number.
I don't know if that would be in the
order domain,
but I think most of that is in there.
OK.
So you can you are able to select your
different orders for the shipments here
Can you show more?
Can you show more information when you
and.
click on the drop down?
No. What do you mean?
Like show more information about each one?
I can.
Right.
So if if I'm looking at that shipment and
I go back to the orders,
just looking at 4 order IDs doesn't tell
me which order I want to look at.
So I wasn't sure if you could show like
the origin,
the destination and the weight for
example, instead of just the order number.
Yeah, so users don't remember this, right?
Mm OK.
And what about this?
Like do you think maybe in this tooltip
preview we could put something there
about that that origin and destination,
something relevant?
Mhm.
Um, I got it. Um.
Then you can also expand this panel to
see everything at once.
And here we have the product place.
I don't know what it's like.
I'm I'm not sure about this part either.
So I think it's the products per order,
right? So.
Yeah.
This is one order selected.
This is these are the products inside
this or this selected order, right?
Yeah, for the products like is it,
can we just default having them open?
OK. So you're like, yeah, OK, good.
Yeah,
cause like I'm looking for the products.
I don't wanna open them, you know,
after I look.
Oh yeah, maybe we can,
we can do it like only the first one
showing up and if you expand it,
everything will be open automatically.
That could be mine.
So because in this view you want some
overview like.
Because here you're you're listing the
orders, right?
Mhm.
Maybe you just need to see one and
because maybe you are more interested in.
OK, so this order has two products, 333,
whatever.
And if you want to see everything we can,
then we can.
Do this automatically.
Well, if I'm looking at the products,
it's usually going to be to say how many
pallets are on there,
which is the 79 bags,
or how many products are hazardous or any
products hazardous.
It's usually to see everything that's on
the shipment, not just.
One order.
OK,
and but you don't need to sum up this too,
right? Yeah, because when it's closed,
it's not showing anything.
It's like just showing the name in the
line.
Yeah, that's what I mean.
When it's closed,
it doesn't have any value.
Oh, OK, OK, got you.
So yeah.
Then we can have the routing guide and
this is also kind of confusing to me.
OK.
Could you like describe it briefly?
What's the purpose of this?
Yeah. So we built the shipment.
We don't have a carrier assigned to it
and the routing guide is basically
looking up contracts that we have agreed
to with our carriers and displaying them
for the for the users. So in this case,
Huh.
the ranking is the sequence that they
should be going through the routing
guides, the.
Number one ranked carrier is usually
going to be the cheapest and they are
also what's it called?
But we we can have a preferred carrier.
So if Conway is constantly late,
we might have the number two carrier,
a higher cost carrier ranked first,
but that that.
That's all controlled from rating, right?
You're just displaying what they give you.
So what this tells me is I can tender to
Conway for $300.
00 and the transit time is going to be
two days.
Three days it looks like.
So sometimes the transit time is
different and that that might make me
choose a different carrier.
There you go. Oh, I see here. One day,
one day, four days.
Yeah, yeah. And then if you scroll back,
the scenario is.
It's unlikely that the carrier 2-3 and
four would be rejected,
declined and pending and the first is
accepted, right?
We usually only go to the second carrier
when the first one declines.
Mhm.
And you can't have a pending tender if
there's also an accepted tender.
OK, so.
So just for you,
like if we were to show operations this,
they would get confused.
Oh, I see.
So it do you think it will be better to
not have this one started?
No, the status is good.
It's just to make it realistic for the
business.
I would make the third carrier accepted
and the first carrier declined, right?
Because you're going to start at the top
and if the first carrier does not accept,
then you go to the second.
OK, so it makes sense. Like this one was.
Yeah, of course.
The the order is important here, right?
Yeah. OK, now I got you. I got you. Yeah.
Right.
OK, sure. Let's go with the next one.
Gender. Well, this is this told me this.
He doesn't need assist yet.
OK.
Uh.
So here well yeah here you see I I I
messed up a little bit because here's
just putting the API error costs side by
side like the summary of both while both
of them are have different like.
You need to see the the different data
sets for both, right?
Yep.
AP total means you have more things.
OK and.
No,
that looks great and this one can be
collapsed because the summary level works
fine.
Oh, this one can be collapsed then, OK.
Yeah,
a lot of times they're not going to need
to go any more detailed than the order
level.
Right.
Give me one second.
Sometimes that happens when you have a
Mac,
you're used to scroll and then when you
lose your where is it?
OK.
And do you have anything else for for
here?
Oh, OK. I see that. Yeah. No,
this looks great. I haven't.
I know we want to show this. I haven't.
Um.
Seen any of it or thought about how I
want it to look, but this looks great.
Yeah, it looks very nice.
And then the completed cost.
And I don't know if this.
Yeah, that's that's correct. After PGI,
the one thing I'm with the plan cost.
Uh.
Um.
It's probably just it's not a UI thing.
I think we have to discuss with Janna how
does this display before it's tendered?
Because we won't know.
I don't know if we'll know the AP cost or
the AR cost until it's tendered,
so we might want to confirm that.
See. So you need to be first, yeah.
Yeah, that's a good one.
But for demo purposes,
I think it's fine to have it right.
Yeah, yeah, it's great. Yeah,
that that that's a back end requirement.
I don't think that impacts your user
interface.
OK. OK. That's good to know as well.
So it's margin. Yeah.
Do you need this? Maybe uh,
principle or like sport it?
Um, I don't.
I don't.
We can have a button here that says yeah.
I don't think we would.
And the tricky part here is this is like
so new to the business.
They're it's it's one of the big things
we're getting out of this project.
So they I don't think they're gonna know
how to answer.
OK, OK, no problem.
Then here I have instructions.
Yeah.
That's it's pretty easy.
So Efrain remark made us that in the
orders domain. Let me go there.
You have this part when you're creating
orders. Um, where is it?
It is here. There you go.
Instruction type BOL and my miscellaneous
and these numbers and he said I'm just
putting the the numbers and the label.
Because it seems like important.
So I just I put it here as well.
So this is like a type of instruction,
right? For example, this is for drivers.
This is for, I don't know anything else.
This is for the load, right?
Yeah.
Yeah,
so that was one of the things the that
So I said.
that was some of the feedback from the
meeting yesterday was like they didn't
want to have the user type or the the
instruction type.
Mhm.
And so that might impact this. I like,
I like the display and I like having the
instruction type,
but they don't have it today and that it
might be easier just to ignore that type
until and and look at it in the future.
OK, so no need of this, OK.
Right. Well,
I'll let you know for sure when we've
finalized the order changes.
OK, then we.
But I I like personally,
the business is saying no.
OK, that's good.
So it's a good feedback, right,
that you got?
Yep. Mhm.
That's some good news then.
Then we have documents.
I don't know what's history Jana didn't
tell me about, she said. Forget about now,
Can you rename history to like audit?
Well, no, no. Keep keep history. OK, I'm.
so just going to documents.
Or it OK.
I'm used to a different system. Go ahead.
Yeah,
and also he told me 10 for history and
history are related. I don't know.
OK.
Maybe we can. I can ask him later.
Then for the documents,
it's for uploading documents, right?
So here you can select what type of
document you want.
Yeah.
Uh, it's an invoice description.
And you can choose the file here.
I can choose something and.
OK,
where did you get the list of documents?
This one.
Yeah.
How Janice PowerPoints I think.
OK.
Well, we would never have an invoice,
but POD would be a good one to replace
Why?
that with.
COD.
Yeah, proof of delivery.
Oh, I see. OK.
I I can put a couple of document types.
Um.
Hopefully that will help a lot because
some stuff I am just guessing you know.
Yeah.
OK, then if we go to notes.
This was very explanatory.
So you add a note and every everyone else
can see it, right?
You can see the the author,
the time and the the notes.
Pretty straightforward.
2.
OK.
Yeah, so I guess notes are related to.
The shipments, right? Yeah.
OK,
so these notes will be showing for this
shipment for example, right?
This which is the selected one.
Yeah, yeah.
And then the stops I should put here over
there, this one over there because OK.
So here's the stops.
Pretty much similar to what different has
a summary and say the pickup.
One question, why do you put D1D2D3?
Does this stop mean something?
Uh.
Oh, this is.
It's good.
01 OK.
Yeah, that's my mistake,
but in in a friend's design is D1.
Oh, OK. So yeah, I'd have to confirm D1.
I don't know if he's saying P1 would be
pick up one, P2 would be pick up two,
and then D1 would be delivery one.
OK. OK. Yeah,
that makes more sense actually, right?
Yeah,
the stops I would move over to be in
between product and routing guide in the
sequence there.
That's all right. Oh, OK.
So this order is important. Yeah. OK.
Yeah.
And I don't know if it's if there's an
easy way to kind of condense that because
when I look at the stops,
I'm interested in the location.
Most interested in the location and the
date.
The location and the date.
Yeah.
Oh, I see. OK,
I will make sure it has that there.
OK and.
But this this is in, this is for internal.
So like they're gonna be more interested
in seeing the data than and not scrolling
than having the fancy screen here.
So if you can make that slimmer so they
can see it all together.
I think that would be good.
Limer like vertically so they you don't
need to scroll it.
Right.
Oh, I see.
So you mean you don't need this like?
If you if you do it,
just just tighten it up is all.
Maybe.
Hmm, OK.
What else?
I think that's that's pretty much it.
Also here is the panel for like arranging
the columns.
OK, yeah.
I still need to work on this so you can
have different column profiles and
everything.
OK.
This panel will be the same thing as the
search filter.
For example if we search and order the
number and we can open the filter that
which should be here right panel.
Yep.
And for example here as we said the other
day,
just give me a second and we can also
open or saved queries for searching
something although.
OK. Yeah.
It's queries will be like only filter
queries won't be like won't store the the
the the search itself,
the value you know it will be just
filtering like quick quick action for
filtering.
OK.
And here we have export SCV.
That's the other discussion that Jack and
Jana and Caitlin were having.
So I did it this way.
Here you can export all which is which
has a limit.
Or the filtered one. For example,
if I do C34C3 shipment,
we have eight items.
We don't have two 200 anymore.
So if we export it,
I can export all of them.
Right now I have 200 in my database.
Otherwise,
we'll be exporting the app records.
Because I this that's what I'm I am.
I am filtering. Make sense.
OK, yeah.
And yeah,
then let me finish this because I still
need to work on. Oh,
and the other thing is the yeah,
this tool tips, right?
Yeah.
Orders that they have and here as well
you see all of the first network public
started.
And here Jana told me about the
interactions. This one's.
To tender, retender, council, accept,
decline.
So I think here is where we need the
actions to be make for displaying some of
the things here as well, right?
For example here or.
Mhm.
OK.
Um, OK, I think that's it.
Awesome. Yeah, looks great.
And it is, yeah.
And I don't need to tell you this is
Yeah, it's cool, isn't it? Much better.
Much better.
definitely like the most complex I think
we have. So nice one.
Yeah, it is.
That's why it's important to have this
kind of approach to work on these things.
Otherwise static designs will know that
it's too much confusion.
So we need this to engage with you more
with you like I I refer to everyone.
So everyone can see,
have feedback and then better
Mhm.
understanding and so on.
OK.
Yep. Perfect.
Perfect.
OK, one more question.
So do you think this tooling could be
provided by Odyssey?
Like I don't wanna like I don't have
problems with working on my own tooling,
but I will be more comfortable if that is
something everyone agrees.
OK, I'll, I'll see what I can. Yeah, I'll,
I'll look into it.
Right. Notebook LA.
I don't know the process here.
OK, just ask and see if it's possible.
But these are safe tools that are made by
OK.
Google and and on Tropic.
It's not like a third party anything, OK?
Yeah, perfect.
OK. Um, thank you, David.
All right. Thank you, Manuel.
Yeah. Bye-bye.
Bye.